Okay, let's start class.
好的，开始上课。
So let's review where we are.
先回顾一下我们现在的位置。
We are discussing or exploring why
我们正在讨论或探索为什么
the United States would want to invade Iran.
美国会想入侵伊朗。
And so far we have two good reasons.
到目前为止，我们有两个好理由。
The first good reason is called the Israel lobby.
第一个好理由叫做以色列游说。
There are in the Israel lobby millions of Christian Zionists
以色列游说中有数百万基督教犹太人
who believe that a conflict in Middle East,
他们认为中东的冲突，
especially between Israel and Iran,
尤其是以色列与伊朗之间的冲突，
will bring Jesus back to earth.
将把耶稣带回地球。
They want their God, Jesus, to return to earth
他们想让他们的上帝耶稣回到地球。
and they believe that
并且他们相信
a war in the Middle East will force him to return.
中东的战争会迫使他归来。
That's the first reason.
这就是第一个原因。
Second reason is the idea of an empire.
第二个原因是帝国观念。
America is an empire and
美国是一个帝国，且
as an empire it has a lot of privileges.
作为帝国，它拥有许多特权。
For example it can just print as much money as it wants.
例如，它可以随意印制大量货币。
Right? US dollars.
对吧？美元。
Right now America is thirty four trillion dollars in debt
现在美国已负债三十四万亿美元，且每两个月债务再增一亿美元。
and the debt is going by ten dollars every two months.
America can do this as long as it is an empire.
美国只要是帝国就能做到这一点。
As long as people fear America.
只要人们害怕美国就行。
But America But as we discussed in the last class,
但正如我们在上一课讨论的那样，
with Putin's invasion of Ukraine,
随着普京入侵乌克兰，
people are now starting to rebel against the empire
人们现在开始反抗帝国，
and therefore
于是
America must demonstrate it still
美国必须证明它仍是世界的军事实力霸权，并且可以通过入侵伊朗来实现。
is the military hegemon of the world and
therefore it can do this by invading Iran.
美国必须证明它仍是世界的军事实力霸权，并且可以通过入侵伊朗来实现。
Today we look at the third and
今天我们来看看中东冲突的第三个也是最后一个推动力。
final force driving conflict in the Middle East.
它真的是沙特阿拉伯与伊朗之间的冲突。
And it's really the conflict between Saudi Arabia
这场冲突的核心是沙特阿拉伯。
and Iran.
和伊朗。
Most people think that
大多数人认为，
Iran's major enemy in the
伊朗的主要敌人是
Middle East is Israel.
中东是以色列。
In fact, Iran's major enemy is Saudi Arabia.
实际上，伊朗的主要敌人是沙特阿拉伯。
These two are bitter rivals.
这两国是激烈的对手。
And to understand why, we have to look at their history.
为了理解原因，我们得先看看它们的历史。
Okay? Okay? So the year is 1979.
好吧？好吧？那么年份是1979年。
And at the start of 1979,
而且1979年初，
Saudi Arabia and Iran are very good friends.
沙特阿拉伯和伊朗关系非常好。
Okay? So let's look at a map of the Middle East.
好吧？那我们来看看中东地图。
Iran is here.
伊朗在这里。
It's next to Iraq.
它在伊拉克旁边。
Saudi Arabia is down here.
沙特阿拉伯在这里。
Then this is Egypt.
然后是埃及。
You have Yemen here.
你这里有也门。
Oman. This is the Strait of Hormuz.
阿曼。这是霍尔姆兹海峡。
And this is the Suez Canal.
这就是苏伊士运河。
Okay? The Red Sea, basically.
好的？红海，基本上。
And in 1979,
然后在1979年，
Saudi Arabia and Iran were very good friends.
沙特阿拉伯和伊朗非常好朋友。
They had a lot of similarities. They were both monarchies.
它们有很多相似之处，都是君主制。
They were ruled by a king.
它们由国王统治。
They were secular. They relied on American rule.
它们是世俗的，依赖美国统治。
They had American power to defend itself.
他们拥有美国的力量来保卫自己。
And they were both oil exporters.
他们都是石油出口国。
Both very prosperous oil exporters.
两者都是非常繁荣的石油出口国。
But then, in 1979,
但随后，在1979年，一场政治地震彻底改变了中东的格局。
a political earthquake
radically changed the landscape of the Middle East.
但随后，在1979年，一场政治地震彻底改变了中东的格局。
In 1979, there was a bottom -up
1979年，出现了自下而上的革命，称为伊斯兰革命。
revolution called the Islamic Revolution.
在1979年之前，...
Before 1979,
there was a general consensus agreement in the Middle East
在中东形成了普遍共识
that religion and
宗教与
politics would be separated.
政治将分离。
But in 1979,
但在1979年，
the people in Iran demanded three things.
伊朗人民提出了三项要求。
Okay? First, they demanded that
好的？首先，他们要求
the king,
国王，
they would not be ruled by a king.
他们将不再由国王统治。
Okay? That's the first demand.
好的？这就是第一个要求。
Second is that the U.S.
第二点是美国不干预国内政治。
should not interfere in domestic politics.
should not interferein domestic politics.
Remember that before the king,
记住，国王之前，沙皇得到了美军的支持。
the Shah, was supported by the American military.
沙皇之前，国王得到了美军的支持。
And the third demand is that
第三个要求是……
as a Muslim people, as people
作为穆斯林民族，作为人们
who believe in the Islamic religion,
谁相信伊斯兰宗教，
the government should be focused on the Islamic religion.
政府应聚焦伊斯兰宗教。
And the fourth demand is that the government should be focused on Islamic law. Okay?
第四个要求是政府应聚焦伊斯兰法。
So, in the referendum,
于是，在公投中，
98% of the people of
98%的伊朗人投票成立伊斯兰共和国，取代君主制。
Iran voted to install an Islamic republic to replace their monarchy.
And this was completely unexpected.
这件事完全出乎意料。
And this caused an earthquake throughout the Middle East.
这件事在中东掀起一场地震。
In November of 1979,
1979年11月，
600 religious leaders were killed.
600位宗教领袖被击毙。
And the religious extremists tried to besiege Mecca.
随后宗教激进者试图包围麦加。
Okay? Mecca is the holiest city in the Islamic religion
麦加是伊斯兰教最圣的城市。
because it's the birthplace of the prophet Muhammad.
因为它是先知穆罕默德的诞生地。
600 extremists tried to take the city over
600名激进者试图占领该城并夺取三件物品。
and demand three things.
并要求三件事物。
Okay? That the Saudi Arabian monarchy should abdicate.
好的？沙特阿拉伯王朝应该让位。
The United States should remove itself
美国应该从沙特阿拉伯的永恒事务中退出。
from the eternal affairs of Saudi Arabia.
And Saudi Arabia should be governed by Islamic law. Now,
并且沙特阿拉伯应由伊斯兰法治理。现在，
this revolt was crushed by the military.
这场起义被军队镇压。
But from that day on, Iran
但从那天起，伊朗
and Saudi Arabia became bitter enemies.
和沙特阿拉伯成为了激烈的敌人。
Because they were both trying to install their vision.
因为两国都在争取各自的愿景。
The vision of Islam on the Middle East.
愿景即在中东铺设伊斯兰的格局。
Okay? So,
好的？所以，
this rivalry between Iran
这场伊朗与沙特阿拉伯的竞争有三种形式。
and Saudi Arabia took three forms.
and Saudi Arabiatook three forms.
Okay? The first form is religious.
好的？第一种形式是宗教的。
So, even though they're both Muslim countries, Islamic countries,
所以，虽然它们都是穆斯林国家，伊斯兰国家，
they have different versions of the religion.
它们有不同的宗教版本。
Okay? So,
好的吗？所以，
Saudi Arabia is Sunni.
沙特阿拉伯是逊尼派。
And Iran is Shiite. Now,
伊朗是什叶派。
you may ask what the difference between
你可能会问这两种宗教分支之间的区别是什么。
these two different branches of the religion are.
答案是，
And the answer is,
no one actually knows.
没有人真正知道。
It's a very complicated issue.
这是一个非常复杂的问题。
The major difference is this.
主要区别在于此。
In 610, the prophet Muhammad was killed.
610年，先知穆罕默德被杀。
And the prophet Muhammad in Medina, in the city of Medina,
先知穆罕默德在麦地那城。
he had a vision to found a new religion called Islam.
他有异象，创立了新宗教伊斯兰。
Okay? And
好的？然后
he spread this religion throughout the Middle East,
他把这门教传播到中东，
throughout the Arab world, forever transforming the Middle East.
再到阿拉伯世界，永远改变了中东。
When he died, there's a problem of succession.
他去世后，出现了继承问题。
Who would succeed the prophet as the leader of the religion?
谁会接替先知，成为宗教的领袖？
The Shiite people believed that
什叶派人认为
only people of Muhammad's
只有穆罕默德血脉的人才能成为宗教的领袖。
bloodline can be the leaders of the religion.
逊尼派不同意，并说……
The Sunni disagreed and said that
anyone who proved himself competent
任何证明自己有能力并忠于宗教的人都可以成为领袖。
and faithful to religion could be the leader.
于是，数百年来，这两大派别交替掌权。
And so, for hundreds of years, these two groups,
And so, for hundreds ofyears, these two groups,
the Sunni and the Shiite, fought a war over the succession of the religion.
逊尼派与什叶派因宗教继承而交战。
And this led to a bitter rivalry that's lasted to this day.
这场战斗孕育了至今仍在延续的激烈竞争。
Okay? Now, the majority of people in the world,
现在，世界上多数人是逊尼派。
about 8%, are Sunni.
约8%，是逊尼派。
Okay? The majority of Muslims in the world are Sunni.
好的？世界上多数穆斯林是逊尼派。
10% are Shia.
10%是什叶派。
Okay? So, why this is important is
好的？所以这点重要的原因是
that Saudi Arabia is a Sunni country.
沙特尔阿拉伯是逊尼国家。
And Iran is a Shia country.
伊朗是什叶国家。
And at the time of the revolution,
在革命时期，
Iran dedicated itself, committed itself,
伊朗把自己奉献给，
to spreading the Shia revolution throughout the world.
把伊斯兰教派革命传播到世界各地。
Okay? Now,
好的？现在，
Saudi Arabia considers itself the leader of the Islamic world
沙特尔阿拉伯把自己视为伊斯兰世界的领袖
because it is home to both Mecca
因为它拥有麦加
and Medina, which
和麦地，哪是伊斯兰世界最神圣的两座城市。
are the two holiest cities in the entire Islamic world.
它们都是伊斯兰宗教最重要的城市。
And they are both the most important Islamic religion.
And they are both the mostimportant Islamic religion.
As you may know, there's a requirement
正如你所知，穆斯林有一项要求
that as a Muslim,
作为穆斯林，
you must take a Hajj,
你必须完成朝觅
a pilgrimage to Mecca and Medina once in your lifetime.
一次在你一生中去麦加和麦地的朝觅。
Okay? And because Saudi Arabia controls Mecca
好的？而且因为沙特阿拉伯掌管麦加和麦地，真是沙特的根本。
and Medina, that's really the source of Saudi
这正是沙特的根本。
Arabia's authority over the Islamic world.
沙特对伊斯兰世界的权威。
Iran says... Iran argues that...
伊朗说……伊朗认为……
Iran argues that because Saudi Arabia is ruled by a king,
伊朗认为因为沙特由国王统治，
that's anti -Muslim.
那是反穆斯林的。
And because United States is defended by the U.S.
而且美国由美军守护，亦是反穆斯林。
military, that's also anti -Muslim.
military, that'salso anti -Muslim.
Saudi Arabia is a heresy.
沙特是异端。
Okay? So, Iran is dedicated itself
好的？所以，伊朗把自己奉献给颠覆沙特的权威。
to subverting Saudi Arabia's authority.
好的？现在，沙特是逊尼派。
Okay? So, this is all makes sense so far.
好的？所以，到目前为止一切都说得通。
Okay? Now, Saudi Arabia is Sunni
好的？现在，沙特是逊尼派。
and
和
it practices the most extreme
它实行最极端的
form of Sunni religion called Wahhabism.
一种被称为瓦哈比派的逊尼宗教形式。
Okay? Wahhabism. In 1744,
好的？瓦哈比派。1744年，
the Wahhabis, okay,
瓦哈比派，好吗，
which again are the most extreme Islamic group,
再次是最极端的伊斯兰团体
made an alliance with the Al -Saad family of Saudi Arabia.
与沙特阿拉伯的阿尔-萨阿德家族结盟。
And the agreement was this.
协议内容是这样：
That the Wahhabis could...
瓦哈比派能……
Wahhabism would become the national religion of Saudi Arabia
瓦哈比派将成为沙特阿拉伯的国教
and
和
the Wahhabis would swear allegiance to the Al -Saad family.
瓦哈比派将向阿尔-萨阿德家族宣誓效忠。
Okay? But
好的？
in the 1930s,
1930年代，
oil was discovered in Saudi Arabia.
油在沙特阿拉伯被发现。
In fact,
事实上，
Saudi Arabia proved to have the most valuable oil resources.
沙特阿拉伯拥有最宝贵的油资源。
In all the world.
全世界都如此。
Okay? And at that time, as the world was modernizing, oil was becoming more and more important.
好吧？那时，随着世界现代化，油变得越来越重要。
And so, that made Saudi Arabia extremely wealthy.
于是，沙特阿拉伯变得极其富裕。
And as it became more and more wealthy, it tried to become more Western,
随着财富的积累，它努力变得更西化、更世俗、更进步、更现代。
more secular, more progressive, more modern.
Which brought it into conflict with the Wahhabis.
这使它与瓦哈比派发生冲突。
Okay? Now,
好吧？现在，
Wahhabism accounts for 20 to 40% of the world's oil.
瓦哈比主义占全球石油的20%到40%。
Of all the people in Saudi Arabia.
在沙特阿拉伯的所有人中。
So, it is a very significant group.
因此，它是一个非常重要的群体。
More important,
更重要的是，
Wahhabi people tend to be extremely fanatical.
瓦哈比人往往极具狂热。
So, for example, in 1979, the people who
例如，1979年，包围麦加的人是瓦哈比人。
laid siege to Mecca were Wahhabis.
他们的行动显示了极端的热情。
And Wahhabis were also responsible for terrorist attacks against tourists,
瓦哈比人也负责对游客的恐怖袭击，
against foreigners in Saudi Arabia.
对沙特阿拉伯的外国人。
Okay? So,
好的？那么，
Saudi Arabia has always had this problem with the Wahhabis.
沙特阿拉伯与瓦哈比人一直有这个问题。
And a way that
而沙特阿拉伯曾试图以此方式解决。
Saudi Arabia has tried to resolve
Saudi Arabia hastried to resolve
the conflict is to export
冲突是为了出口
the religion of Wahhabism throughout the world.
瓦哈比宗教遍及世界
So, for example,
比如说，
Osama Bin Laden was a
奥萨马·本·拉登是
Saudi citizen responsible for spreading Wahhabism in Afghanistan.
沙特公民负责在阿富汗传播瓦哈比主义。
And that's what started Al -Qaeda.
这就是阿尔-卡达的起因。
Okay? So,
好的？那么，
Saudi Arabia is trying to export Wahhabism.
沙特阿拉伯正在传播瓦哈比主义。
Iran is trying to export the Shiite religion.
伊朗正试图把什叶派宗教输出。
And so, they come to conflict with each other.
于是两国相互冲突。
So, the first source of tension between Iran
于是，伊朗之间的第一个紧张源头是
and Saudi Arabia is over religion.
而沙特阿拉伯已超越宗教。
Second is economical.
第二点是经济方面的。
And what that means is that
这意味着
both countries are oil exporters.
两国都是石油出口国。
In fact,
实际上，
Saudi Arabia is completely reliant on oil for its economy.
沙特阿拉伯的经济完全依赖石油。
40% of Saudi
40%属于沙特
Arabia's economy GDP is based on oil exports.
沙特的GDP基于石油出口。
Saudi Arabia is number one oil exporter in the world.
沙特阿拉伯是世界第一大石油出口国。
Okay? 75% of government revenues comes from its oil exports.
好的？75%的政府收入来自石油出口。
In other words, Saudi Arabia does not actually collect taxes from its citizens.
换句话说，沙特阿拉伯并不从其公民那里征税。
It just sells oil.
它只是卖石油。
Okay? Iran also sells oil.
好吧？伊朗也卖石油。
It's the number four oil exporter in the world.
它是世界第四大石油出口国。
But it's less reliant on oil because it has a diversified economy.
但它的经济已多元化，油的比重已不大。
Meaning that it has very strong human capital.
意味着它拥有非常强大的人力资本。
It has a very well -educated population
它拥有一支非常受过教育的人口。
that does all sorts of different activities.
那样做了各种不同的活动。
Okay? Science, art, education.
好吧？科学、艺术、教育。
So, Saudi Arabia for the longest time has been trying to control the price of oil in order to maximize profits.
于是，沙特阿拉伯长期以来一直试图调控油价，以最大化利润。
For example, it wants to cut back production in order to increase the price of oil,
例如，它想削减产量，以提升油价。
which will increase profits. But
这将增加利润。但
Iran often doesn't cooperate because
伊朗往往不合作
Iran is trying to sell as much oil
伊朗正尽可能多卖油，以提振经济。
as possible in order to boost its economy.
as possible in orderto boost its economy.
Okay? So, there's economic conflict between these two countries.
好的？所以这两国之间有经济冲突。
And the third and
而第三点是……
final conflict is geopolitical.
最终冲突是地缘政治的。
Okay? And geopolitical means that
好？而地缘政治意味着……
both countries are trying to exert
两国都在努力施展……
as much influence as possible over the Middle East.
尽可能多地影响中东。
Now, Iran is trying to exert influence over the Middle East
现在伊朗正试图在中东施展影响力。
because after the revolution in 1979,
因为1979年革命之后，
Iran was trying to control the oil prices.
伊朗正试图控制油价。
Now, many countries, including Saudi Arabia and the United States,
现在，许多国包括沙特阿拉伯和美国，
encouraged Iraq to invade Iran.
鼓励伊拉克入侵伊朗。
And this invasion, called the Iraq -Iran War,
并且这场被称为伊拉克-伊朗战争的入侵，
lasted eight years and
持续了八年，
it cost the lives of millions of Iranians.
耗费了数百万伊朗人的生命。
And from then on,
从那时起，
Iran has adopted a policy
伊朗采取了一个积极干预的政策，
of aggressive intervention in the
在……
Middle East in order to distract the United States and Israel.
中东以此扰美以此扰以色
Okay? So, for example, in Israel,
好？比如在以色，
there are two groups opposing Israel, Hamas
有两伙对抗以色，
and Hezbollah.
以及真哈伊德。
And they're both financed and
它们都由伊朗资助并
supported politically by Iran.
并得到伊朗的政治支持。
And the point of doing this is to distract Israel.
并且这样做的要点是扰动以色。
Okay? Now, Saudi Arabia is trying to exert influence over the Middle East
好？现在，沙特阿拉伯正试图在中东施展影响力。
because as the number one oil exporter,
因为它是第一大油出口国，
it needs to control shipping lanes.
它需要掌握航运通道。
Okay? It needs to control this area
好？它需要掌握这片区域
and this area, the Strait of Hormuz and the Suez Canal.
以及这片区域，即霍尔木兹海峡和苏伊士运河。
And 40% of all the world's oil passes through these two straits
并且40%的全球石油通过这两条海峡
and they go mainly to East Asia, China,
主要运往东亚，中国
South Korea, and Japan mainly.
南韩和日本主要。
Okay? So, because
好？所以，因为
of these geopolitical tensions,
这些地缘政治紧张的结果，
Iran and
伊朗和
Saudi Arabia have fought against each other.
沙特阿拉伯两国互相交战。
They fought three proxy wars.
他们打了三场代理战。
They fought three shadow wars.
The first is in Iraq.
第一场在伊拉克。
And now in Iraq, as you know, in 2003,
在2003年，正如你所知，阿美入侵伊拉克并把国家摧毁。
America invaded Iraq and destroyed the country.
现在在伊拉克，正如你所知，2003年美国入侵伊拉克并把国家摧毁。
And after they destroyed the country, there's a power vacuum.
随后他们摧毁了国家，形成了权力真空。
And so, basically, Iran came in
于是，基本上伊朗介入了。
and tried to take over the country.
并试图接管该国。
And it could do so because
于是它能做到这一点，因为
two -thirds of the population were Shiite.
三分之二的人口是什叶派。
And therefore, they had affinity with Iran.
于是他们与伊朗有亲缘。
And a third were Sunni.
第三部分是逊尼派。
So, what happened was that
于是发生的事是……
to counter the Iranian influence in Iraq,
为抵消伊朗在伊拉克的影响力，
Saudi Arabia started to finance the
沙特开始资助一半的逊尼派对抗什叶派。
one -third of the Sunnis against the Shiite.
于是，伊拉克在入侵后爆发了一场激烈的内战。
So, there was a very violent civil war fought in Iraq after the invasion.
（两行）
Okay? Many people also believe
好的？很多人也认为
that Saudi Arabia is responsible for the war.
沙特是战争的责任方
And they're responsible for the financing of the Islamic State.
他们负责为伊斯兰国融资
Okay? Or ISIS.
好的？或者ISIS。
Because ISIS really hates the Shiite religion.
因为ISIS真的很讨厌什叶派宗教。
Okay? But over time,
好的？但随着时间的推移，
because Iran has been
因为伊朗已经
so much more effective in projecting its power than Saudi Arabia,
如此更有效地投射其海权比沙特更远
basically, Iran now controls much of Iraq.
基本上，伊朗现在控制了伊拉克的大部分
Okay? So, in this first war, Iran defeated Saudi Arabia.
好的？所以，在这场第一次战争中，伊朗击败了沙特。
Then they fought another war in Syria.
随后他们又在叙利亚打了一场战争。
Syria's leader, Assad,
叙利亚的领袖，阿萨德。
faced a rebellion.
面临叙利亚内战。
And Saudi Arabia,
以及沙特。
America, Israel support the rebels against Assad.
美以支持叙利亚内战。
And Iran came in to support Assad as well as Russia.
以及伊朗也来支持阿萨德和俄罗斯。
And over time, Assad was able to crush the rebellion.
随着时间推移，阿萨德终于能压制叙利亚内战。
Okay? So, in the second proxy war,
好吧？于是，在第二场代理战争中。
Iran won as well. Now, there's another proxy war in Yemen.
伊朗也赢了。现在又有一场在也门的代理战争。
Okay? And it started in 2016.
好吧？它从2016年开始。
So, the wars in Iraq
于是，伊拉克的战争。
and Syria, they were important to Saudi Arabia.
以及叙利亚，它们对沙特阿拉伯很重要。
But they didn't really threaten Saudi Arabia.
但它们并没有真正威胁沙特阿拉伯。
But this war in Yemen did threaten Saudi Arabia.
但这场在也门的战争确实威胁沙特阿拉伯。
Okay? So, for the longest time,
好的？于是，最长时间里，沙特阿拉伯支持也门的政治领导。
Saudi Arabia supported the Yemen political leadership.
然后，胡塞人发动了叙起。
And then there was a rebellion by the Houthis.
胡塞人是住在山里的什叶派村民，试图推翻政府。
Okay? The Houthis.
好的？胡塞人。
The Houthis were Shia villagers
胡塞人是住在山里的什叶派村民。
who lived in the mountains.
他们住在山里。
And they were trying to over -throw the government.
他们正试图推翻政府。
And Saudi Arabia was afraid that
沙特阿拉伯也担心
the Houthis would become political leaders.
胡塞人会成为政治领袖。
So, Saudi Arabia lost a massive invasion of Yemen.
于是，沙特阿拉伯在也门的大战中失利。
It was 150,000 Saudi Arabian troops.
共有15万沙特阿拉伯军队。
They had war planes.
他们拥有战机。
They were backed by the most advanced American weapons
他们得到了最先进的美军武器和技术。好吗？
and technology. Okay?
他们还拥有约30个国家的联合军团，包括埃及。
They also had a coalition of about 30 nations including Egypt
and the UAE.
和阿联。
Saudi Arabia named this operation decisive storm, right?
沙特阿拉伯把这次行动称为决定性风暴，对吗？
Which sounds like that's a storm.
听起来像是风暴。
And the strategy they use is what we call shock and awe.
并且他们采用的策略就是我们所说的冲击与震撼。
And shock and awe is basically we have so
冲击与震撼基本上就是我们拥有的……
many bombs, we have so many airplanes,
我们拥有的……飞机……
we have so many soldiers that we can in about a week's time destroy you, okay?
我们拥有这么多士兵，约一周内就能把你们打垮，行吗？
So go in, go fast, be decisive, destroy your enemy.
快点进攻，果断行动，消灭敌人。
Unfortunately this for Saudi Arabia did not work
可惜这招对沙特阿拉伯没起作用。
and the reason why is first of all the Houthis were in the mountains
以及原因是，首先胡塞人位于山地
and so your bombs didn't really stop them.
于是你的炸弹并未真正击中他们
In fact all your bombs did was make them really angry
实际上你所有的炸弹只是让他们更愤怒
because if your bombs you were killing civilians
因为你的炸弹会杀死平民
So you're basically uniting the entire population against you.
于是你基本把全体民众团结在你这边
That's the first problem. Second problem is
这就是第一个问题。第二个问题是
that the Houthis are in the mountains,
胡塞人位于山地，
but Saudi Arabia has oil fields.
但沙特有油田。
And guess what, guys?
你猜怎么了，伙计们？
It's really, really easy to blow up oil fields.
真的很容易炸毁油田。
So that's what the Houthis are doing.
于是胡塞人就是这么干的。
They're sending these cheap drones, they might cost $1,000,
他们派出这些便宜的无人机，可能只值一千美元。
$10,000, and they'll blow up oil fields and ports.
$1万，随后他们会炸油田和港口。
Saudi Arabia has another problem.
沙特还有一个问题。
Saudi Arabia has no fresh water.
沙特没有淡水。
It's in the desert.
它在沙漠里。
It is a desert. No water, guys.
它是沙漠。没有水，大家。
No rivers. So
没有河流。
it relies entirely on desalination plants.
它完全依赖于海水淡化厂。
And this is extremely impressive technology.
这是一项极其令人印象的技术。
It takes salt water, sea water, and turns it into fresh water.
它把盐水、海水变成淡水。
It's very impressive. But it's on the coast.
非常令人印象。但它在海岸上。
And guess what, guys?
你们猜怎么了？
The coast. So
海岸。
Iran can blow up these plants, and the Houthis can blow up these plants as well.
伊朗能炸毁这些工厂，胡塞也能炸毁这些工厂。
So Saudi Arabia basically lost this war
所以沙特阿拉伯基本上输了这场战争。
because
因为
the Houthis could inflict massive economic damage on Saudi Arabia.
胡塞人可以给沙特阿拉伯造成巨大的经济损失。
Okay? So from this war, Saudi Arabia learned three things.
好的？所以从这场战争里，沙特阿拉伯学到了三件事。
Okay? The first thing it learned is that
好的？第一件事是它学会了……
if it wants to defeat their enemies,
如果想打败他们的敌人，胡塞、叙利亚人和伊拉克人，他们也需要能打败伊朗。
the Houthis, the Syrians, and the Iraqis,
they also need to be able to defeat Iran.
如果想打败他们的敌人，胡塞、叙利亚人和伊拉克人，他们也需要能打败伊朗。
Okay? That's the first thing they learned.
好的？那是他们学到的第一件事。
The second thing they learned is that
第二件事是他们学到的……
their economy is extremely vulnerable to attack.
他们的经济极易受到攻击。
At any point...
在任何时刻…
Iran, with its missiles and drones,
伊朗，凭借其导弹与无人机，
could destroy the entire Saudi Arabian economy.
可摧毁整个沙特阿拉伯经济。
Okay? It can easily blow up all the oil fields and the desalination plants.
好的？它可以轻易炸毁所有油田和海水淡化厂。
So the third thing that Saudi Arabia learned from all this is...
于是，沙特阿拉伯从这一切事中学到的第三点是……
We really need America to fight Iran for us.
我们确实需要美国来替我们与伊朗作战。
In the long term,
在长期内，
that's the only way we're going to survive as a nation.
那是我们作为民族国家生存的唯一方式。
Okay? We need to defeat Iran.
好吧？我们需要击败伊朗。
And we can't do it by ourselves.
我们自己做不到。
We need America to do it for us.
我们需要美国来替我们做。
Okay? Unfortunately for Saudi Arabia,
好吧？对沙特阿拉伯来说不幸的是。
in 2001,
在2001年，
9 -11 happened.
9-11发生了。
Right? Fifteen of the nineteen
对吗？19个中有15个。
hijackers were citizens of Saudi Arabia.
劫机者是沙特阿拉伯公民。
Which meant that America was very unhappy with Saudi Arabia.
这意味着美国对沙特阿拉伯非常不满意。
Okay? Americans didn't like Saudi Arabia.
好吧？美国人不喜欢沙特阿拉伯。
Americans also knew that there were a lot of human rights abuses in Saudi Arabia.
美国人也知道沙特阿拉伯有很多人权侵害。
The other thing that happened is in 2003,
另外一件事是2003年，
America invaded Iraq.
美国入侵伊拉克。
Saudi Arabia tried to exert as much influence as possible in Washington,
沙特阿拉伯试图在华盛城发挥尽可能大的影响力，
D.C. to stop the war.
D.C. 以停战为目标。
Because they knew that
因为他们知道
if America invaded Iraq, it would make Iran more powerful.
如果美国入侵伊拉克，伊朗会更强大。
Now as you know, Saudi Arabia could not stop the war.
正如你所知，沙特阿拉伯无法阻止战争。
Okay? In 2008,
好？2008年，
Obama,
奥巴马，
Barack Obama, came into office.
巴拉克·奥巴马上任时，
And Barack Obama's understanding of the world was
巴拉克·奥巴马对世界的理解是
that, okay, the Middle East is a complete mess.
那，好的，中东一团糟。
And it's hopeless. I don't really want to deal with the Middle East.
而且它已经没救了，我也不想再去管中东。
Plus, China is rising.
再说，中国正在崛起。
The main threat to American power in the future will be East Asia.
未来美军的主要威胁将来自东亚。
So he proposed something called the Asia Pivot, which
于是他提出了一个叫做“亚洲枢纽”的计划，且
is to transfer American military resources
它是把美军资源转移到东亚。
from the Middle East to East Asia to counter the threat of China.
从中东到东亚，以对抗中国的威胁。
But to do that,
但要做到这一点，
you needed to reduce tensions in the Middle East.
你需要在中东降低紧张。
And so in 2015, he made a deal.
于是在2015年，他达成了一笔交易。
He made a deal with Iran called the Iran Nuclear Deal.
他与伊朗签订了伊朗核协议。
And the deal was basically, Obama said to Iran,
并且这笔交易基本上是，奥巴马对伊朗说，
listen, I know you're trying to develop nuclear weapons.
听着，我知道你们正在尝试研制核武器。
Okay? So what we're going to do is,
好的？所以我们接下来要做的是，
if you promise to not develop nuclear weapons,
如果你承诺不研制核武器，
we will live economic sanctions on you
我们将对你实施经济制裁。
so that you can prosper.
以便你繁荣。
And Iran said yes.
并且伊朗回答是。
Okay? And this really scared Saudi Arabia.
好？这让沙特尔很惊。”
Because if America leaves the Middle East
因为如果美国离开中东并与伊朗达成和平，
and brokers a peace with Iran,
沙特尔将会非常脆弱。
then Saudi Arabia would be extremely vulnerable.
然后沙特尔将极度脆弱。
Okay? So
好？于是……
Saudi Arabia became very, very desperate.
沙特尔变得非常非常绝望。
Its very existence was threatened.
它的存在本身就受威胁。
Also, the economic outlook for Saudi Arabia was not
此外，沙特尔的经济前景也不算太好。
that great.
Remember, the entire economy was under threat.
记住，整个经济都在威胁之中。
The entire economy depended on oil. But guess what, guys?
整个经济依赖石油。但你们猜猜，兄弟们？
Oil is a finite resource.
石油是有限资源。
Eventually, you're going to run out of oil.
最终，你会耗尽石油。
Okay? Now, if you're optimistic,
好了？现在，如果你乐观，
you'll be like, well, Saudi Arabia would run out of oil in about seven years' time or eight years' time.
你会说，嗯，沙特尔大约七年后或八年后就会耗尽石油。
Okay? But there are also some people who believe that
好的？但也有人认为
Saudi Arabia will run out of oil in about ten years' time.
沙特尔大约十年后会耗尽石油。
And if Saudi Arabia has no oil, then its entire economy collapses.
如果沙特尔大没有石油，整个经济就会崩溃。
Okay? Then
好的？然后
you also have a problem with global warming, right?
你也有全球变暖的问题，对吧？
Climate change.
气候变化。
You also have a problem with the entire global economy is slowing down.
你也有一个问题，整个全球经济正在放缓。
Therefore, the demand for oil is decreasing.
因此，石油需求在下降。
So the economic outlook for Saudi Arabia, it's extremely grim.
所以，沙特尔大经济前景非常黯淡。
Okay? And that's why...
好吧？这就是原因……
In 2017,
2017年，
Saudi Arabia appointed a new
沙特尔阿拉伯国任命新
leader called Mohammed bin Salman, okay?
领袖叫做穆罕默德·本·萨尔曼，好吗？
The Crown Prince. Whoever calls MBS.
王储。谁叫MBS。
And MBS promised to be a new leader.
MBS承诺成为新领袖。
He was young.
他很年轻。
He was progressive.
他很有进取心。
He wanted women to drive.
他想让女性开车。
He wanted young people to go to the movie theater.
他想让年轻人去看电影。
Okay? And he proposed a new vision for Saudi Arabia.
好吧？他还提出了一个新的愿景。
Called Vision 2030.
称为“愿景2030”。
Okay? But MBS' most important achievement is
好的？但MBS最重要的成就是他与新总统唐纳德·特朗普成了朋友。
that he became friends with the new president, Donald Trump.
好的？于是2016年，...
Okay? So in 2016,
Donald Trump became President of the United States.
唐纳德·特朗普当选为美国总统。
And MBS decided that
并且MBS决定这是一场机会，让沙特阿拉伯成为领袖。
this is an opportunity for Saudi Arabia to become a leader.
这是一场机会，让沙特阿拉伯成为领袖。
To reset relations with America.
重建与美国的关系。
Okay? So, Trump,
好吧？于是，特朗普，
his first trip outside
他的第一次出国行程是去沙特阿拉伯。
the United States was to Saudi Arabia.
the United Stateswas to Saudi Arabia.
That was the first achievement.
那是第一个成就。
Second achievement is that
第二个成就就是。
MBS became best friends with Trump's son -in -law,
MBS与特朗普的女婿成了最佳朋友。
Jared Kushner. Okay?
贾德·库什纳。好吧？
And Jared Kushner was Trump's Middle East advisor.
而贾德·库什纳是特朗普的中东顾问。
And his job was to bring peace to the Middle East.
他的工作就是为中东带来和平。
Mainly between Israel and the Arab countries.
主要是以色列与阿拉伯国家之间。
And to that extent, Kushner did a great job.
并且在这方面，库什纳干得很不错。
Because MBS helped him.
因为MBS帮了他。
So, his major achievement is something called the Abraham Accords.
所以，他的主要成就是所谓的《亚伯拉罕协定》
The Abraham Accords is just to establish peace between the Arab countries.
《亚伯拉罕协定》只是为了在阿拉伯国家之间建立和平。
Between Israel and the Arab countries.
在以色列与阿拉伯国家之间。
So that they can unite against Iran together.
于是他们可以联合对抗伊朗。
So, MBS was looking very good.
于是MBS看起来非常不错。
But then in 2018,
但随后在2018年，
he did something
他做了件事
that scared the world.
那让世界惊恐。
Okay? MBS was a visionary.
好的？MBS是个有远见的人。
He had a plan for where to take Saudi Arabia.
他有个把沙特阿拉伯带向何方的计划。
He wanted to modernize Saudi Arabia.
他想让沙特阿拉伯现代化。
But he was also young.
但他也很年轻。
He was a tyrant. He did not like people
他是个暴君。他不喜欢人。
who criticized him.
他曾批评他。
Okay? So, there's a journalist named Jamal Khashoggi.
好的？所以，有一位记者叫贾马尔·卡什戈吉。
Who worked for the Washington Post.
他曾在《华盛邮报》工作。
And who was a permanent resident of the United States.
并且他是美国的永久居民。
He was a Saudi national. And
他是沙特国人。并且
MBS had him killed. And this caused an international uproar.
MBS下令其被杀。并且这引发国际轰动。
Okay? The CIA, the US government, conducted an investigation.
好的？美国中央情报局和政府开展调查。
And they determined that it was MBS who ordered the assassination.
他们确定是MBS下令的刺杀。
Trump protected MBS.
特朗普为MBS提供保护。
Okay? And then,
好吧？然后，
the most important thing that Trump did was,
最重要的事是特朗普做的，
In January 2020,
2020年1月，
Trump ordered the assassination of a man named Qasem Soleimani.
特朗普下令杀害一名叫卡塞姆·苏莱米尼的人。
Who is considered to be the second most powerful man in Iran.
他被认为是伊朗第二位最有权势的人。
After the Ayatollah.
在阿亚图拉之后。
Okay? The supreme religious leader of the country.
好吧？该国的最高宗教领袖。
It is Qasem Soleimani who
是卡塞姆·苏莱米尼
is responsible for Iran's policies
负责伊朗在伊拉克战争、叙利亚战争和也门战争的政策
in the Iraq war, the Syria war, and in the Yemen war.
在伊拉克战争、叙利亚战争和也门战争中负责伊朗的政策
Okay? So, from the perspective of Saudi Arabia,
好的？从沙特阿拉伯的角度来看，
Qasem Soleimani is public enemy number one.
卡塞姆·苏莱米尼是第一公敌。
He is the greatest threat to Saudi Arabia.
他是沙特阿拉伯最大的威胁。
Now, before,
现在，先说一下，
okay, America had many opportunities to assassinate Qasem Soleimani.
好的，美国曾有多次机会刺杀卡塞姆·苏莱米尼。
George W. Bush had the opportunity.
乔治·W·布什也曾有机会。
Barack Obama had the opportunity.
巴拉克·奥巴马也有机会。
And both, both believed
两者都认为
that doing so
这样做是必要的。
would cause basically World War III.
会导致世界大战三。
Okay? Because if you kill Qasem Soleimani,
好？因为你杀了卡塞姆·苏莱米尼，
the number two leader of Iran, Iran would have no choice
伊朗第二号领袖伊朗将无计可施。
but to go to war with you.
但要去和你开战。
And that's why they both refrained from killing Qasem Soleimani.
这就是他们两者都不杀卡塞姆·苏莱米尼的原因。
In fact, when
事实上，当
Trump made the decision to assassinate Soleimani,
特朗普决定暗杀苏莱米尼，军方震惊一片。
the entire military was stunned.
军方全员惊呆了。
Okay? They couldn't believe this was happening.
他们都不敢相信这件事发生了。
So, how does this happen?
那么，这一切是怎么发生的？
Okay. So, for some time, there was some conflict between U.S.
好的。所以，曾经一段时间，美国士兵与伊拉克的什叶派民兵之间出现冲突。
soldiers and Shia militiamen in Iraq.
soldiers and Shiamilitiamen in Iraq.
And the Pentagon thought it had to act.
并且五角部认为必须行动。
Okay? So, in these situations,
好吧？在这些情况下，
they had to go to the president and present options to the president of how best to respond.
他们必须向总统提交方案，说明最佳应对方式。
And usually, the Pentagon will design the choices
并且，五角部通常会设计这些选择
so that the president does what the Pentagon thinks is best.
以便总统能按五角部认为最佳的方式行动
Okay? So, an example is that
好吧？举个例子是这样
if I'm in the military and I go to Trump, I give you three choices.
如果我在军队里去找特朗普，我会给你三个选择。
Okay? The first choice is A.
好吧？第一个选择是A。
One, let's do nothing. Okay?
一，先不做事。
Two is what you should do.
二是你应该做的事。
And three is let's blow up the world.
三是让世界炸开。
Okay? So, when I present these three options to you,
好了，当我把这三种方案呈现给你时。
you as a president, being wise and
你作为总统，聪明地
strategic, will obviously always pick option two.
战略上，显然会一直选择第二个方案。
Right? What you should do.
对吧？你应该做的事。
What the military suggests you should do.
军方建议你应该做的事。
Okay? Unfortunately, in this instance,
好了？不幸的是，在这一次，
Trump chose option three.
特朗普选择了第三个方案。
Let's blow up the world, guys.
我们来炸世界吧，伙计们。
And so, they assassinated Qasem Soleimani.
于是他们暗杀了卡塞姆·苏莱曼尼。
Okay? So,
好了？所以，
in other words, it is very likely
换句话说，很可能
that if Trump stayed a second term,
如果特朗普连任期都能连任，
the United States would have gone to war with Iran,
美国会与伊朗开战
given how things were progressing.
鉴于事态进展
Okay? MBS was
好了？MBS很高兴
so happy about all this that
关于这一切
he once bragged privately to a friend that, oh, Jared Kushner,
他曾私下对朋友夸耀，哦，贾德·库什纳，
Trump's son -in -law, the man responsible for all Middle East policy,
特朗普的女婿，负责中东政策的那个人，
well, he's in my pocket.
嗯，他在我手里。
Meaning I own him.
意思是我掌握着他。
Okay? And the evidence that suggests this is
好？并且有证据表明如此。
that after Trump left office,
那在特朗普离任后，
after Jared Kushner left office,
那在贾德·库什纳离任后，
Jared Kushner set up a private equity fund.
贾德·库什纳设立了一个私募股权基金。
And MBS and
以及MBS和
the Saudi government invested $2 billion into the fund.
沙特政府向该基金投入20亿美元。
Okay? Does that make sense?
好？这样说对吗？
So, we don't know how,
于是，我们还不确定，但看起来是这样的
we don't know this for sure, but it seems like
我们还不确定，但看起来是这样的
Trump is doing exactly what the Saudis want,
特朗普正做沙特人想做的事，就是激化与伊朗的紧张关系。
which is to inflame tensions with Iran.
这正是沙特人想要的，让与伊朗的紧张关系再度激化。
Okay? And this suggests
好？这说明
that if in November,
如果在十一月，
Trump wins a second term,
特朗普赢得第二个任期
it is very possible
很可能
that Trump will declare war on Iran.
特朗普会对伊朗宣战
Or at the very least,
至少
continue to escalate tensions with Iran.
继续与伊朗升级紧张局势。
Okay? Which will very likely lead to World War III.
好？这很可能导致第三次世界大战。
So, in that respect, we can say that,
所以，在这方面，我们可以说，
the election in November,
十一月的选举，
whether or not Trump comes back into office,
特朗普是否再次上任，
is one of the most consequential elections.
是最重要的选举之一。
Okay? Does that make sense, guys?
好的？这有道理吗，大家？
Okay, any questions?
好的，有问题吗？
Anything you want me to clarify before we end class?
还有什么想让我在结束前说明的吗？
Okay. So,
好的。那样，
what we will do next class is figure out if Trump,
接下来我们要做的事是弄清楚特朗普会不会在十一月赢得选举。
will win in November.
And I will make the argument to you that it is almost
我会向你们提出论点：他在十一月获胜几乎是确定的，极有可能。
very certain, very likely, that he will win in November.
好吗？那样，下一节课我们来探讨原因。
Okay? So, we will examine why next class.